{"name": "65B  2014-12 Asia", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The rectangular box shown below has its dimensions given in centimeters. What is the volume, in cubic centimeters, of the box?", "choices": {"A": "34", "B": "120", "C": "328", "D": "656", "E": "960"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. The lowest temperature on a winter morning was -11\u00b0F. Later that same day the temperature reached a high of 22\u00b0F. By how many degrees Fahrenheit did the temperature increase?", "choices": {"A": "-11\u00b0F", "B": "-2\u00b0F", "C": "11\u00b0F", "D": "22\u00b0 F", "E": "33\u00b0F"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to 5(3x) - 5y + 10 + 14y ?", "choices": {"A": " 37xy", "B": " 27xy + 10", "C": "15x + 19y + 10", "D": "15x +  9y + 10", "E": "15x +  9y - 10"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. The 15-member math club needs to choose a student government representative. They decide that the representative, who will be chosen at random, should NOT be 1 of the 2 officers of the club. What is the probability that Nico, who is a member of the club but NOT an officer, will be chosen?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. Two parallel lines are cut by a transversal. The measure of one of the angles formed is 136\u00b0. What is the measure of the smallest angle formed ?", "choices": {"A": "22\u00b0", "B": "44\u00b0", "C": "46\u00b0", "D": "112\u00b0", "E": "136\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. Let a function of 2 variables be defined by f(x, y) = xy - (x - y). What is the value of f(13, 18) ?", "choices": {"A": "31", "B": "203", "C": "229", "D": "239", "E": "265"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to \"one-third of z multiplied by the sum of x and y\" ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. A craft show was held in a local park. Booths were set up along the various footpaths in the park. The booths, represented by dots, and the footpaths, represented by line segments, are shown in the diagram below. Visitors must enter the park at point A and exit the park at point B. Travel is restricted to the footpaths, and visitors can only move in the directions indicated by the arrows. How many different routes can a visitor take through the park?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "6", "C": "8", "D": "10", "E": "12"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. What is  of 48% of $5,000 ?", "choices": {"A": " $ 30", "B": " $ 300", "C": " $ 1,920", "D": " $ 3,000", "E": " $ 19,200"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. If , then x = ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " -14"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. In \u0394RST, RT \u224c ST and \u2220R measures 35\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220S ? ", "choices": {"A": " 35\u00b0", "B": " 55\u00b0", "C": " 65\u00b0", "D": " 110\u00b0", "E": " 145\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12.  For x\u22600 and y\u22600, which of the following expressions is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13.  Using a cereal box, Royce constructs a small car whose side panels are 2 inches by 6 inches. He decides to use the packing box from the family's new refrigerator to make a 12: 1 scale replica of his cereal-box car for his younger sister to play in. What should the dimensions, in inches, be of the side panels of the packing-box car?", "choices": {"A": " 2 by 72", "B": " 3 by 4", "C": " 3 by 18", "D": " 14 by 18", "E": " 24 by 72"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. Which of the following is closest to the number of yards of fencing needed to fence the perimeter of the triangular flower bed shown below\uff1f", "choices": {"A": " 20.5", "B": " 22.4", "C": " 24.9", "D": " 25.5", "E": " 26.5"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. In Section 5.2 of the textbook Ms. Belfiores uses for her class, the practice problems are numbered 1 through 50. For homework, she assigned only the problems whose numbers were multiples of 3. The answers for all odd-numbered problems are given in the back of the textbook. For how many of the assigned problems was the answer NOT given in the back of the textbook?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 6", "C": " 8", "D": " 16", "E": " 25"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16.  Puakea scored 72, 80, 88, 64, and 76 on 5 class tests. She was given the option to take a bonus test. With her bonus test score replacing her lowest score on the 5 class tests, her test average was 81. What was her score on the bonus test?", "choices": {"A": " 69", "B": " 77", "C": " 81", "D": " 89", "E": " 106"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17.  The height y, in feet above the ground, of a ball dropped from a height of 16 feet can be modeled by the equation y = -16t2 + 16, where t is the time in seconds after the ball is dropped. According to this model, how many seconds after the ball is dropped will it be 7 feet above the ground?", "choices": {"A": " 1", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. Use the following information to answer questions 18-20.The gas tank in Mark's car has a fuel capacity of 18 gallons of gasoline. The car averages 24 miles per gallon when driven at highway speeds and 21 miles per gallon when driven at city speeds. Approximately 90% of the 30, 000 miles Mark drives each year are at highway speeds. The average price of Mark's gasoline is $1.699 per gallon.18. Mark filled his gas tank on Monday. Later that week, the fuel indicator showed 3 gallons of gasoline remaining in the tank. Of the following statements, which best represents the number of miles, m, Mark had driven since filling the gas tank on Monday?", "choices": {"A": " m &lt; 315", "B": " m &gt; 432", "C": " m &gt; 504", "D": " 315 \u2264  m \u2264 360", "E": " 378 \u2264  m \u2264 432"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. Use the following information to answer questions 18-20.The gas tank in Mark's car has a fuel capacity of 18 gallons of gasoline. The car averages 24 miles per gallon when driven at highway speeds and 21 miles per gallon when driven at city speeds. Approximately 90% of the 30, 000 miles Mark drives each year are at highway speeds. The average price of Mark's gasoline is $1.699 per gallon.19. Mark filled his gas tank at a highway oasis and continued driving on the highway. Of the following graphs in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, which best represents the relationship between gallons of gasoline remaining in Mark's gas tank and miles driven since the tank was filled?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. Use the following information to answer questions 18-20.The gas tank in Mark's car has a fuel capacity of 18 gallons of gasoline. The car averages 24 miles per gallon when driven at highway speeds and 21 miles per gallon when driven at city speeds. Approximately 90% of the 30, 000 miles Mark drives each year are at highway speeds. The average price of Mark's gasoline is $1.699 per gallon.20. Which of the following is closest to the average cost of gasoline per mile when Mark drives his car at city speeds?", "choices": {"A": " $0.07", "B": " $0.08", "C": " $0.09", "D": " $0.10", "E": " $0.11"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21.  If a = -1 and b = 1, which of the following inequalities orders the 4 expressions below from smallest to largest?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. Elyssa wants to graph the line with equation 5x - 3y = 6 on her graphing calculator, which requiresthe equation to be solved for y. Which of the following is Elyssa's equation solved for y?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Which of the following is equivalent to the expression 5(c - 3) - 2(c + 4) ?", "choices": {"A": " 7c + 1", "B": " 7c - 7", "C": " 3c + 1", "D": " 3c - 7", "E": " 3c - 23"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24.  If (x + 1)(x - 1) = 8, then (x2 + x)(x2 - x) = ?", "choices": {"A": " 18", "B": " 63", "C": " 72", "D": " 81", "E": " 90"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. In the figure below, \u0394ABC and \u0394BAD are right triangles such that \u2220ABC \u224c \u2220BAD, \u2220C \u224c \u2220D, and AB \u224c AB. Which of the following congruence criteria applies directly to show that \u0394ABC \u224c \u0394BAD?(Note: The symbol \u224c means \"is congruent to.\")", "choices": {"A": "AAS (If 2 angles of a triangle and the side opposite one of those angles are congruent to the corresponding parts of another triangle, then the triangles are congruent.)", "B": " HL (If the hypotenuse and 1 leg of a right triangle are congruent to the corresponding parts of another right triangle, then the triangles are congruent.)", "C": " LL(If the 2 legs of a right triangle are congruent to the corresponding parts of another right triangle, then the triangles are congruent.)", "D": " SAS (If 2 sides and the included angle of a triangle are congruent to the corresponding parts  of another triangle, then the triangles are congruent.)", "E": " SSS (If 3 sides of a triangle are congruent to the corresponding parts of another triangle, then the triangles are congruent. )"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. At a particular time, the distance between the surfaces of 2 planets, P1 and P2, is 97,000,000 kilometers, as shown in the figure below. The diameter of P1 is 12,000 kilometers. Which of the following expressions in scientific notation represents the number of kilometers from the center of P1 to the surface of P2?(Note: The figure is NOT drawn to scale.)", "choices": {"A": " 9.7006 \u00d7 107", "B": "9.7012 \u00d7 107", "C": " 1.09 \u00d7 108", "D": " 5.82 \u00d7 1011", "E": " 1.164 \u00d7 1012"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. In the figure below, C is on AD and BE, and \u0394ABC is similar to \u0394EDC. What is the measure of \u2220ACB ?", "choices": {"A": " 42\u00b0", "B": " 44\u00b0", "C": " 50\u00b0", "D": " 65\u00b0", "E": " Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28.  The perimeter of a rectangle is 48 inches. The length of the rectangle is 5 times the width. What is the length, in inches, of the rectangle?", "choices": {"A": " 4", "B": " 8", "C": " 12", "D": " 20", "E": " 40"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29.  On the last algebra exam,  of the students enrolled in the class received A's and  of the students who received A's had perfect scores. On that exam, 3 students received perfect scores. How many students are enrolled in the class?", "choices": {"A": " 8", "B": " 9", "C": " 21", "D": " 24", "E": " 27"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30.  A jar contains at most 50 jelly beans. If the number of jelly beans is divided by 5, the remainder is 3; if the number of jelly beans is divided by 7, the remainder is 0. How many jelly beans are in the jar?", "choices": {"A": " 22", "B": " 28", "C": " 38", "D": " 48", "E": " 49"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31.  If x \u2260 0, y\u2260 0, and x \u2260 y, which of the following is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. In the figure below, ABCD is a rectangle with F on AB and E on AD. The dimensions shown are in inches. What is the area, in square inches, of \u0394EFC ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " 18", "C": " 31", "D": " 41", "E": " 49"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33.  A grocery store carries 2 brands of cat food, Brand A and Brand B, both sold only in 20 1b bags. The regular price per bag of Brand A cat food is $4 more than the regular price per bag of Brand B cat food, which is $b per bag. This week, each bag of Brand A cat food is on sale for 50% off its regular price. Which of the following is an expression for the sale price per bag of Brand A cat food in terms of the regular price per bag of Brand B cat food?", "choices": {"A": " 0.50b + 4", "B": " 04b + 0.50", "C": " 0.50(b + 4)", "D": " 4(b + 0.50)", "E": " b + 0.50(4)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. For what value of k does the line with equation 4x + ky = 11 pass through the point (2, -3) in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane ?", "choices": {"A": " -1", "B": " ", "C": " 1", "D": " 2", "E": " 3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Use the following information to answer questions 35-37.The section of the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below includes the points A(5, 2) , B(-4, 2), and C(-4, 5).35. Which of the following is the midpoint of AC ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Use the following information to answer questions 35-37.The section of the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below includes the points A(5, 2) , B(-4, 2), and C(-4, 5).36. What is the length, in coordinate units, of AC ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " 50", "E": " 90"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Use the following information to answer questions 35-37.The section of the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below includes the points A(5, 2) , B(-4, 2), and C(-4, 5).37. tan \u2220CAB = ?", "choices": {"A": " -3", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " 3"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38.  Which of the following is the real number line graph of the solution set for x of the inequality |x + 2| - 3 &gt; 0 ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. A circle in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane has center (7, -11) and radius 5 coordinate units. Which of the following is an equation of the circle?", "choices": {"A": "(x - 7)2 + (y + 11)2 = 5", "B": " (x + 7)2 + (y - 11)2 = 5", "C": "(x + 7)2 - (y - 11)2 = 5", "D": " (x + 7)2 - (y - 11)2 = 25", "E": " (x - 7)2 + (y + 11)2 = 25"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Intersecting lines p and q and the letter \"F\" are shown in the figure below. After \"F\" is reflected across line p and then reflected across line q, the resulting orientation of \"F\" is shown in one of the following figures. Which one is it?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41.  If 2h + 3c = x and 3h + 2c = y, then x + y is how many times as large as h + c ?", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " 3", "C": " 4", "D": " 5", "E": " 6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. The quarter circle in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below has a radius of 20 inches. A ray from the origin forms a 30\u00b0 angle with the positive x-axis. What are the coordinates of the intersection of the ray and the quarter circle?", "choices": {"A": "(10, 10)", "B": " ", "C": "(10, 10\u03c0)", "D": "(10\u03c0, 10)", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43.  In a certain physical education class at Franklin High School, 3 of the students are on the golf team, 5 are on the soccer team, 9 are on the basketball team, and 10 are not on any of these teams. The seasons for these sports do not overlap, so it is possible for a student to be on more than 1 of the teams. What is the smallest possible number of students that could be in this physical education class?", "choices": {"A": " 13", "B": " 15", "C": " 19", "D": " 21", "E": " 27"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44.  Which of the following is the least common denominator for the expression below?", "choices": {"A": " 5 \u00b7 11", "B": " 5 \u00b7 11 \u00b7 13", "C": " 5 \u00b7 11 \u00b7 132", "D": " 52 \u00b7 113 \u00b7 132", "E": " 54 \u00b7 115 \u00b7 132"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The line through L(0, 4) and M(6, 0) is drawn in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. Each point on the line is translated 2 units to the right and 1 unit up so that the image of M has coordinates (8, 1). What is the slope of the line resulting from the translation?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46.  In her daily workout, Anna runs at a constant rate of 8 miles per hour and walks at a constant rate of 4 miles per hour. Today, she ran for 10 minutes, walked for 5 minutes, ran for 10 minutes, stopped to rest for 5 minutes, and then ran for 5 minutes. In the following graphs, the horizontal axis represents the elapsed time since the beginning of Anna's workout and the vertical axis represents the distance Anna covered. Which graph best represents Anna's workout for today?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. In which quadrant(s) of the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, shown below, does the graph of 6x -2y = 11 have NO points?", "choices": {"A": " Quadrant I only", "B": " Quadrant II only", "C": " Quadrant III only", "D": " Quadrants I and IV only", "E": " Quadrants II and III only"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48.  What is the value of the product (log636)(log464) ?", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " 5", "C": " 6", "D": " 8", "E": " 96"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The points A(-5, -3) and B(1, 4) lie in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. What is the slope of any line perpendicular to ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50.  What is the positive difference between the median and the mode of the data set 3, 5, 11, 3, 8?", "choices": {"A": " 1", "B": " 2", "C": " 3", "D": " 5", "E": " 6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. For each positive integer x with 5 as its largest prime factor, which of the following is NOT necessarily a factor of x2 ?", "choices": {"A": "x", "B": " 5x", "C": " 5", "D": " 10", "E": " 25"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. When (x + 1)10 is expanded (multiplied out with like terms combined) , the first term is x10 and the last term is 110. How many other terms are there besides the first and last terms?", "choices": {"A": " 0", "B": " 1", "C": " 8", "D": " 9", "E": " 11"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. The tables below give the values of the function f(x) and the values of the function h(x) for various integer values of x. For what value of x is it true that f(h(x)) = 3 ?", "choices": {"A": " -1", "B": " 0", "C": " 1", "D": " 2", "E": " 3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Garnette is making an arrangement of toothpicks. As shown in the figure below, the arrangement is an isosceles trapezoid formed by a single row of equilateral triangles with sides 1 toothpick long. The entire arrangement uses 59 toothpicks. How many toothpicks are used for the top base of the isosceles trapezoid?", "choices": {"A": " 12", "B": " 14", "C": " 15", "D": " 24", "E": " 25"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55.  Whenever   is defined, it is equivalent to which of the following expressions?(Note: sin(2a) = 2(sin a)(cos a) for all real numbers a.)", "choices": {"A": " 1", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. The figure below shows 2 intersecting lines. The angle measures are positive and are given in degrees. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to 180 - a ?", "choices": {"A": " a + d", "B": " a + 2d", "C": " 2a + b", "D": " b + c", "E": " c + d"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57.  A piece of wire 20 inches long is bent to form a right triangle. One of the legs of the triangle is 5 inches long. How many inches long is the other leg of the triangle?", "choices": {"A": " 5", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " 12"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. If the radius of the circle below is 6 inches, and point O marks the center, how many inches long is arc  ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. Aidan is fishing on a lake. As shown in the figure below, his hook is caught on the bottom of the lake at the end of 60 feet of fishing line that extends from the end of his fishing pole. The angle of depression from the end of his fishing pole to his hook is 20\u00b0. If the tip of his fishing pole is 5 feet above the surface of the water, which of the following is closest to the number of feet his hook is below the surface of the water?(Note: sin 20\u00b0 \u2248 0.34 and cos 20\u00b0 \u2248 0.94)", "choices": {"A": " 15", "B": " 20", "C": " 25", "D": " 51", "E": " 56"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. In the figure below, a regular octagon is inscribed in a circle of radius r. Each side of the octagon is a diameter of a shaded semicircle. What is the ratio of the total area of the 8 semicircles to the area of the circle?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "4 sin2 22.5\u00b0 : 1", "D": "8 sin2 22.5\u00b0 : 1", "E": " 4 sin2 45\u00b0 : 1"}, "correct": "C"}]}